ombwatch.org 2015-06-09

# Privacy Statement | Center for Effective Government

We respect your right to privacy! Any and all personally identifiable information collected at this site will not be sold or rented, or otherwise disclosed for commercial purposes or activities not consistent with the mission of this organization except pursuant to judicial order. Users or subscribers will receive no cookies (unless it is beyond our control), charges, or downloads from us unless voluntarily agreed to by the user. Any personally identifiable information you give the Center for Effective Government such as your name, address, telephone number, etc., will be held with the utmost care, and will only be used in ways that are consistent with the mission of this organization. A more detailed explanation about how we care for your personal information is described below. If you have any questions, [please let us know](mailto:ombwatch@foreffectivegov.org).

* * *

The Center for Effective Government does not knowingly allow other organizations or services to track individual visitors to our Web site. Our site captures limited information about visits to our site, but we use this information only to analyze general traffic patterns (e.g. what pages are most/least popular) and to perform routine system maintenance. We may choose to have a voluntary registration system, including a guest book or other approaches to voluntarily providing personally identifiable information. If you choose to provide personally identifiable information, we will only use the information for purposes consistent with the mission of this organization. Information, including e-mail addresses, submitted through our web contact and feedback forms is handled by secure servers. [Online contributions to the Center for Effective Government](https://secure3.convio.net/ombw/site/Donation2?1340.donation=form1&df_id=1340) are transmitted using SSL encryption.

The Center for Effective Government maintains several e-mail lists, and individuals may always choose whether they want to be on a list or not. We do not sell, rent, or otherwise disclose the addresses on our lists. In addition, we configure our list server software to refuse to divulge the e-mail addresses of our list subscribers to anyone but authorized staff and list administrators.

To protect your e-mail privacy, we configure our mail servers to refuse relays and use various anti-junk-mail services to block spammers from our lists.

We allow individuals to use our [FedSpending.org](http://www.fedspending.org/) and [RTK NET databases](http://www.rtknet.org/) at no charge. We encourage users to identify who they are in order to encourage their participation in policy matters consistent with the mission of this organization. We do not intentionally permit user access privileges to mass mailers or re-mailers.
